We will now talk about the use of tabs, pills and
我们接下来将会学习 标签页 胶囊式标签页和页签导航
tabbed navigation to enable presentation of content to the user.
在呈现内容给用户方面的一些应用
Obviously on any website there is a lot of content that can be presented to the user.
显然对于任何一个网站 都有海量的内容可以呈现给用户
But if we organize it in a way that is easy to navigate the content,
但如果我们能将我们的内容 规划排版得好一些
then the visitors may find it more easy to find the information that they want.
访问者将能更加容易地获取他们想要的信息
So, tabs and pills allow us to organize the content appropriately.
而标签页和胶囊式标签页正是能够很好地 组织你想呈现的内容的东西
Now, tabs and pills provide the navigational elements for us.
它们都提供了一些导航元素
And then the content itself is enclosed in tabbed pills,
然后内容则将会被封装在 一个个标签胶囊中
as we will see when we go through this lesson.
我们接下来将会看到一些实例
Let's take a look at a simple example of how we can use tabs and
让我们先看一个简单的实例
tabbed navigation to organize content.
在这个栗子里 我们想要呈现的是
So in this case we are looking at the information about the corporate leadership
我们餐厅的合作伙伴的
of our restaurant.
领导人的一些信息
Now the content which was listed all together has been organized into tabs
如图所示 这些信息像胶囊一样被优雅地 放在了一个个标签下面
indexed by the name of the corresponding leader here.
这些标签的标题则是这些领导人的名字
So using the tabbed navigation we can easily move between
这就是页签导航的一个典型应用
the various descriptions of the different leaders using
有了它 我们就能轻松地查看 我们想要了解的领导人的信息了
the tabbed navigation provided for us there.
事实上 页签导航
This enables the visitors not to be overwhelmed with a lot of content but
让访问者免于被信息淹没不知所措
instead see the content presented in an organized manner.
作为替代 它让信息变得更有组织性
So as we see, the tab and pills provide us with the navigation elements
这个简单的栗子已经比较好地说明了 胶囊式标签页在
to be able to navigate the content that is already organized into multiple panes.
组织和导航内容上的威力
Let's now look at a simple example to understand how we go about implementing
让我们接下来看一看
tabbed navigation on our page.
如何具体地实现这个简单的栗子
To implement tabbed navigation we're gonna use a UL with the classes nav nav-tabs.
为了实现页签导航 我们需要用到 ul 标签
So this is a nav element, as we see.
并且对其我们要设置 class="nav nav-tabs"
So that's why we use the nav class.
其中 nav 表明着这将会是一个导航元素
And then the other qualifier is the nav-tabs class there.
nav-tabs 则起着定制样式的作用 我们下面将会提到这是什么意思
Now within that, each list item will be presented as a tab.
然后在这个 ul 下面 每一个 li 标签都需要设置
So you can see in this code here the different list items presented
role="presentation"
are laid out on the screen as tabs seeing the example above.
这个设置会实现 如屏幕上方的图片中的效果
Each of these tab elements carries a a tag
然后在每个 li 下面则是一个 a 标签
with an href which we can use to defer to the tab pane
对其要通过 href 属性来指定 这个 a 标签导航到的地方
that we're going to include next with the actual content of the tab.
指定的方法有很多 这里我们用的是指定 id
Also, one of the list items will be marked as active.
需要注意的是 在所有这些 li 中 有一个是要设置 class="active" 的
This means that that particular tab will be opened by default when
这意味着它将会是在当前网页被访问时
the user navigates to this location on the page.
默认打开的标签页
Instead of using the nav tabs class, we can use the nav pills class.
我说过 nav-tabs 是拿来定制样式的 所以作为替代 我们可以用 nav-pills 来获得另一种样式
The nav pills class turns the navigational elements into a list of items
它和 nav-tabs 的区别仅仅在于外观
and the item marked as active will be
通过对比现在屏幕上方的图
clearly highlighted on the page there.
和之前屏幕上方的图
So you can see that since I applied the active class to the first element,
我相信你可以找到它们的不同之处
the corresponding a tag has been
需要注意的地方也是一样的 就是对其中一个 li 设置 class="active"
clearly marked out as a pill on the script.
我在这里是设置了第一个 li 为 active 所以第一个 li 看上去就和一个胶囊长得很像
But both nav tabs and nav pills provide exactly the same functionality.
总而言之 nav-tabs 和 nav-pills 提供的功能
Depending on how you want to design your user interface, you may choose one or
是一毛一样的
the other as the approach for designing your navigational elements.
你只用基于外观来选择你到底要用哪个
To the navigational elements, we can also apply the nav-justified class.
需要注意的是 我们还可以应用 nav-justified 这个类
When you do that the nav elements will stretch
当你需要让你的导航元素充满
the entire width of the parent element there and
它所能充满的整行时
will occupy a proportional portion of
你就可以应用它
the screen width for these nav elements.
不过要注意的是 这时各元素会按比例分配宽度
Now elements within the nav class can be disabled by using
我们还可以通过 disabled 类
the disabled class applied to that particular element.
来无效化某个特定的元素
Pills, in addition,
然后就是 pills 会额外地提供你一个方法
provide you with a way of stacking them vertically rather than horizontally.
这个方法允许你让胶囊式标签页竖着堆叠
Nav tabs are always presented in a horizontal arrangement.
而不是如默认般那样横着排列
Nav-pills, on the other hand, can be either presented horizontally, or
nav-tabs 只能横着排列
if you use the nav-stacked class together with nav-pills
nav-pills 则可以通过 nav-stacked 来使各元素
then the items will be stacked vertically on the screen.
在屏幕上竖着叠在一起
We will see the use of nav pills in the next lesson.
在下节课里 我们将会学习 nav-pills 的 各种应用
The actual content that
至于每个标签的具体内容
forms the part of the tab will be enclosed inside a tab pane.
则需要封装在一个 div 下面
So you will have a div with the class tab-pane and
这个 div 需要设置 class="tab-pane"
inside that the content will be presented.
然后在 div 的下面 你就可以把你想放在 标签中的内容都扔进去
Now these tab panes are grouped together inside an outer
最后 你还需要用一个设置了 class="tab-content" 的 div
div with the class tab-content.
把所有这些设置了 tab-pane 的 div 都封装起来
And one of those tab panes will be designated as the active tab pane,
然后其中一个 tab-pane div 则需要设置 class="active"
which means that the content from that tab pane will be visible on the screen
它和之前设置了 active 的 tab 相互呼应
when you first reach that tab item there.
也就是说它是默认呈现的内容
Going back to our example that we presented earlier,
回到我们最初呈现的那个简单栗子
let's look at the actual code used for constructing those nav tabs.
让我们看看它背后的代码吧
So here I present the UL class that enables me to construct the nav tabs.
你可以看到有一个设置了 class="nav-tabs" 的 ul
And also the tab content itself is enclosed inside a tab pane there, and
然后你可以看到 一个 tab-content 和若干个 tab-pane
these tab panes are enclosed inside an outer div with the class tab-content.
它们的层次关系和我之前说的一样
One more point to note is that we need to connect the tabbed
还需要注意的是 我们需要把这两块联系起来
navigational elements to the content page.
这是通过 nav-tabs 下的 a 标签的 href 属性实现的
To do that for each of the tabbed panes we will give an ID, and
通常来说我们在这会使用 id 来指定
the same ID will be used in the list item in the UL class
其对应关系如图所示
to refer to this particular tab there.
我们之前学过如何用 id
So in this example you can see that I have used the IDS Peter for this tab pane,
来指定特定的 HTML 元素
and there comes warning list item in the UL class uses the href to Peter there.
这里的用法和之前是一样的
In addition, for the tabbed navigation elements to work correctly,
最后需要注意的是 为了使这个页签导航正确工作
they should be given the data attribute data toggle equal to tab there.
对 ul 下面的每一个 li, 我们要设置 data-toggle="tab"
Now we will move on to our next exercise where we will actually
那么接下来我们将会进行一个练习
construct the tabs example that you saw earlier.
在这个练习中 我们将亲自实现一个标签页
So we're going to go into the aboutus.html page,
具体而言 我们将会修改我们的 aboutus.html
we're gonna use tabbed navigation to build the tab navigational elements there,
在其中 我们将用一个页签导航 来组织那些内容
and then we're gonna organize the content inside tabbed panes, and
我们将会把每块内容封装进 tab-pane 中
enclose that with a tab content div there.
并把所有 tab-pane 都封装在 tab-content 下 【翻译 - Carefree0910】